dotdash.com 2019-07-10

# Privacy Policy | Dotdash

### Privacy Policy

Updated May 2, 2019

At Dotdash, we take online privacy seriously and we respect the privacy  
concerns of our community of users.  In this policy (the “Privacy  
Policy”), we describe how we collect, use, and share information obtained  
through your use of dotdash.com and its affiliated websites, email properties,  
and other online services, including without limitation, Verywell.com (and its  
affiliated websites), TheBalance.com (and its affiliated websites), Investopedia.com,  
Lifewire.com, TripSavvy.com, Byrdie.com, MyDomaine.com, TheSpruce.com (and its  
affiliated websites), liveabout.com, aboutespanol.com and ThoughtCo.com (collectively, the  
“Sites”), all of which are owned and operated by About, Inc.  
(“Dotdash”,  “we”, “us”, or “our”), to help you make informed  
decisions about how you share information when you visit or use the Sites as  
well as your rights in determining what we do with the information that we  
collect or hold about you.

This Privacy Policy only applies to properties we own and operate and  
does not cover any information collected via any other website, application, or  
service. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or privacy practices  
of third parties.  By using the Sites, you explicitly agree to the  
terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**Understanding How Information Is Collected:**

**Information You May Choose to Provide to Us**

We may collect information, including personal information, from you if  
you choose to provide that information. For example, you may provide us with  
your name and contact information (such as an email address), date of birth, or  
other details of that nature, when you sign up for our newsletters, participate  
in contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions on the Sites, or apply for a job  
with Dotdash.

You also may choose to provide personal information about yourself when  
you participate in surveys, forums or discussions, or other Interactive  
Services on the Sites. Please be aware that information you post may be viewed  
or captured by anyone who visits the Sites, therefore you should avoid posting  
sensitive or personal information that you would not want to be available to  
the public.

**Information That Is Automatically Collected  **

When you access the Sites, we and our third-party partners and service  
providers may automatically collect certain information from your device or  
web-browser about your visit using tools such as cookies, web beacons, and  
other data collecting and tracking technologies, to help us understand how our  
users use the Sites and to target advertising messages to you. We and our  
third-party partners and service providers may also collect and track  
information about your online activities over time and across different websites,  
applications, and devices using certain data matching techniques. The  
information collected automatically when you visit the Sites may include your  
IP address, characteristics of your operating system, information about your  
browser and system settings, data about the computer or mobile device you use  
to access the Sites, unique device identifiers, clickstream data (which shows  
the page-by-page path you take as you browse the Sites), and other information  
that generally is not considered personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Tracking Technologies** ** **

**Cookies**  are small files that many websites and other online services use to  
store information about users on the users’ own devices or computers. The Sites  
use cookies (such as HTTP and HTML5 cookies and Flash cookies), as well as  
other types of local storage in order to provide useful features to our users.  
For more information about cookies, you may visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). See the section below regarding Your choices to learn more  
about how you may limit or disable cookies on your computer. If you choose to  
disable cookies, that could affect your ability to use certain features of the  
Sites that use cookies to enhance their functionality. 

To manage our automatic data collection, we, and our third-party  
partners and service providers, use cookies or similar technologies on our sites to  
collect information that helps us improve the quality of sites and the online  
experience of our visitors and users. 

**Web** ******beacons**  are small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their  
cookies, and they may be used for a variety of purposes, such as counting the  
number of visitors to the Sites, analyzing how users navigate around the Sites,  
assessing how many emails that we send are actually opened and which articles  
or links are viewed by visitors.

We also use third-party web analytics services, such as Google  
Analytics, on the Sites to provide us with statistics and other information  
about visitors to the Sites.  [Click  
here to learn more about Google Analytics and how you may opt out.](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)

Finally, companies that provide certain third-party apps, tools,  
widgets, and plug-ins that may appear on the Sites (for example, Facebook  
“Like” or “Share” buttons), also may use automated means to collect information  
regarding your interactions with these features. This information collection is  
subject to the privacy policies or notices of those third parties. 

**“Do Not Track” Signals** **.**  Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a  
“do not track” signal to websites and online services you visit. At this time  
there is no consensus among industry participants as to the meaning of “do not  
track” in this context. Like many other websites, the Sites are not configured  
to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers. [Click here to learn more about “do not  
track” signals.](https://allaboutdnt.com/)

**Information We Obtain From Other Sources**

We may supplement the information we collect with information from  
third-party partners and service providers, including data brokers, customer  
acquisition vendors, and other companies that collect contact and consumer  
information such as demographic and interest data, in order to learn more about  
our users, better tailor the content and offers we make available to you, and  
for other lawful business purposes.  We may combine the information  
we receive from those other (online and offline) sources with information we collect  
through the Sites. 

**Social Network and Platform Integration**

The Sites may be integrated with social media networks and other  
platforms whereby information may be shared between us and those platforms. For  
instance, if you interact with our Sites through a social media feature such as  
a plug-in, then you may be granting us on-going access to certain information  
from that social media account.  If you do not want a social media  
platform to collect or share information about you, please review the privacy  
policy and privacy settings of the applicable social media property before  
using such features on our Sites. 

**How We May Use Information We Collect**

We, and our  
third-party partners and service providers, may use the information gathered on  
the Sites for various purposes, including the purposes listed  
below.  For example, if you were to contact us with a question and  
provide your email address, we would use the email address you provided to  
respond to your inquiry. In addition, we use information we collect from you  
and through the Sites to:

·       
Provide  
information, products and services you request (such as when you sign up to  
receive our email newsletters) or that we otherwise believe would interest you,  
including promotional offers from us and third party partners;

·       
Respond  
to requests, questions, complaints, and comments, and provide other types of  
user support and customer care;

·       
Direct  
you to portions of the Sites or other third-party websites or services, that we  
believe may interest you;

·       
Customize  
content, features, advertisements or other marketing messages we and third  
parties show you, on the Sites and elsewhere online; 

·       
Process  
and reply to applications for employment with Dotdash;

·       
Communicate  
about, and administer your participation in, events, programs, contests,  
sweepstakes, and other offers or promotions;

·       
Carry  
out, evaluate, and improve our business (which may include without limitation  
developing new features for the Sites; analyzing and enhancing the user  
experience on the Sites; assessing the effectiveness of our marketing and  
advertising; and managing our communications);

·       
Perform  
data analytics regarding usage of the Sites (including market and customer  
research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal  
information);

·       
Guard  
against, identify, and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims, and  
other liabilities; 

·       
Comply  
with applicable legal requirements, law enforcement requests, and our company  
policies; and 

·       
For  
other purposes that are disclosed at the time you provide your information,  
with your consent.

**How We May Share Information**

Our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers may have  
access to information we collect through the Sites to carry out work on our  
behalf.  In addition, certain service providers may collect or access  
information through the Sites to enable or provide services, tools, or other  
features available on the Sites. We also may share information:

·       
With our affiliates for internal  
business purposes;

·       
With third parties for marketing  
purposes, including social media networks, data management platforms, and other  
advertising technology providers; for example, we may match your email  
address with third parties with whom you have also consented to share your email  
address and use such match to deliver custom offers or emails to you on the  
Sites and elsewhere online; 

·      With third parties who  
provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities such as commenting  
and other site functionality. These companies are authorized to use your  
personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us,  
pursuant to written instructions. In such cases, these companies must abide by  
our data privacy and security requirements, and are not allowed ot use PI they  
receive from us for any other purpose

·       
If we are required to do so by law,  
regulation, or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena);

·       
In response to requests from government  
agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, or other governmental bodies, as  
well as to meet national security requirements;.

·       
If we believe disclosure is necessary or  
appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, in connection with an  
investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity, or to protect and defend  
our legal rights or property.

·       
With advertisers and other partners to  
inform them about the nature of our user base;

·       
In the event we sell or transfer all or  
a portion of our business or assets (including a reorganization, dissolution,  
or liquidation). In such an event, we will seek to provide you with  
commercially reasonable notice, e.g., via email and/or notice on our website,  
of any change in ownership, incompatible new uses of your personal information,  
and choices you may have regarding your personal information; and

·       
With your consent or at your discretion.

**Your Privacy Choices**

**Unsubscribe from emails** **.**  To unsubscribe from a particular newsletter, click the  
“unsubscribe” link at the bottom of that email newsletter. If you would like to  
globally opt-out from all email campaigns, please send an email to [optout@dotdash.com](mailto:optout@dotdash.com) with “Unsubscribe” in the subject line. When we send newsletters  
to subscribers we may allow advertisers or partners to include messages in  
those newsletters, or we may send dedicated newsletters and marketing messages  
on behalf of those advertisers or partners. We may disclose your opt-out  
choices to third parties so that they can honor your preferences in accordance  
with applicable laws.

**Blocking cookies** **.**  Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive  
cookies, or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies. If you choose to  
disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features of the Site that  
use cookies to enhance their functionality.

**Disabling local shared objects (“Flash cookies”).**  We may use other kinds of local storage  
that function similarly, but are stored in different parts of your computer  
from ordinary browser cookies, including Flash cookies placed on your device or  
web browser via the Adobe flash plug-in. Your browser may allow you to disable  
its HTML5 local storage or delete information contained in its HTML5 local  
storage. [Click here](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) for further details about deleting  
information contained in “local shared objects” or adjusting related  
preferences.

**Options concerning third-party ad networks** **.**   As described in this Privacy Policy,  
we and third parties may use  
cookies and similar tracking technologies to collect information and infer your  
interests for interest-based advertising purposes. If you would prefer to not  
receive personalized ads based on your browser or device usage, you may generally  
opt out of interest-based advertising by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/).

Please note that you will continue to see advertisements, but such  
advertisements will no longer be tailored to your interests. For more information  
about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can  
visit [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and [click here](http://aboutads.info/choices) to opt out or to learn more about your  
options. You also may visit the [NAI’s  
site for additional options](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) on how to opt out of  
interest-based advertising. 

**_User Access and Choice_**

We respect your control over your  
information and, upon request, we will seek to confirm your identity and whether  
we hold or are processing information that we have collected from you. You also  
have the right to amend or update inaccurate or incomplete personal information,  
request deletion of your personal information, or request that we no longer use  
it. Under certain circumstances we will not be able to fulfill your request,  
such as if it interferes with our regulatory obligations, affects legal  
matters, we cannot verify your identity, or it involves disproportionate cost  
or effort, but in any event we will respond to your request within a reasonable  
timeframe and provide you an explanation. In order to make such a request of  
us, please email us at [privacy@dotdash.com](mailto:privacy@dotdash.com) _._

_Please note that for personal information about you that we have  
obtained or received for processing on behalf of a separate, unaffiliated  
entity–which determined the means and purposes of processing, all such  
requests should be made to that entity directly. We will honor and support any  
instructions they provide us with respect to your personal information. _

**_Data Retention_** __

We  
will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the  
purposes outlined in this Privacy Notice unless a longer retention period is  
required or permitted by law.

**How We Protect Personal Information.**

We maintain reasonable and appropriate administrative, technical, and  
physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide  
against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration,  
access, disclosure, or use. However, it is not possible to guarantee the  
security of information transmitted online. You use the Sites and provide us  
with information at your own discretion and risk. If you have questions about  
the security of your personal information, or if you have reason to believe  
that the personal information that we hold about you is no longer secure,  
please contact us immediately as described in this Privacy Notice. ****

**Links From The Sites to Other Websites**

The Sites may contain links to other websites that are controlled by  
third parties, as well as videos, advertisements, and other content served by  
third parties. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies,  
which we strongly suggest you review. We are not responsible for the content,  
terms of use, privacy policies, or any other aspects of any websites,  
applications, or services that we do not own or control.

**Surveys, Quizzes and Other Features**

While you are visiting the Sites, you may have the opportunity to  
participate in surveys or quizzes, or to use other interactive features that  
request information about you and your opinions and preferences. Your  
participation in these features is entirely voluntary. If you do choose to  
participate, please be aware that these features may be operated by a third  
party that is not controlled by us, and therefore the information you provide  
may be collected by the third party and subject to its privacy policy.

**Children’s Privacy  **

The Sites are intended for a general audience and are not designed or  
intended for use by children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect  
personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that  
we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we  
will delete any such information.

**Users Outside the United States**

If you are visiting the Sites from outside the United States, please be  
aware that information we collect through the Sites will be transferred to and  
stored on our servers in the United States. By using this Sites, you  
acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in  
the United States as described in this online privacy policy. Please be aware  
that the data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data  
transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country  
of residence.

**Our Notice to California Residents**

Subject to certain limits, under California law California residents may  
ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of personal information  
that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties’ direct  
marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity  
of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in  
the [How to Contact Us](https://www.dotdash.com/dash-terms/#how_to_contact) section below to make a request  
for this information.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may update this online privacy policy periodically to reflect changes  
to our privacy practices, such as how we collect or use personal information.  
We will we indicate at the top of this privacy policy the date when it was most  
recently updated. If we propose to make any material changes, we will notify  
you by means of a notice on this page. We encourage you to periodically review  
this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have questions about this policy or about our privacy practices,  
you may contact us by emailing [privacy@dotdash.com](mailto:privacy@dotdash.com). If you are a California resident  
inquiring about your California privacy rights, please include “California  
privacy rights request” in the subject line of your email.

You may also write to:

Dotdash Privacy  
1500 Broadway, 6th Floor   
New York, NY 10036

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.
